Morgane Fortin

Data scientist

33 years, French citizen

🕋 Dublin, Ireland

ganetin@gmail.com

+33 6 70 59 82 21

ganetin.github.io

github.com/ganetin

Technical Skills —

Python C/C++/C# Git GIS/ArcGIS HTML and CSS NLP (NLTK)

Soft Skills -

Independent thinker

Responsible & determined

Excellent communicator

Team builder & project initiator

₩ell-organized and disciplined

Languages -

French **English** Polish Italian German

Personal interests

Sailing for 20+ years

Cinema, literature, opera

Video games

Genealogy

Amateur crypto investor

First aid diploma

Personal Statement

Former astrophysicist turned data scientist bringing 11 years of analytical research experience and dynamism to an organization seeking innovative data-oriented solutions. My adaptability and strong motivation allow me to quickly learn new skills and tools, both in a team and independently. My solid background in problem-solving, programming, and data visualisation, together with my ability to communicate complex ideas across diverse audiences in uncomplicated terms, will be an asset to any organisation.

Education

2012 PhD in Astronomy and Astrophysics Warsaw (PL) & Paris (FR)

> Polish Academy of Sciences & Paris Observatory with highest honors; joint Polish & French Ph.D. programme

2009 **MSc in Astrophysics**

Paris (FR)

Pierre and Marie Curie University, Ecole Normale Supérieure & Paris Observatory – with honors

Work Experience

Oct. - Nov. 2020 **Data Scientist - SEGRO plc**

Web scraping in C# (System.Net.Http, HTML Agility Pack, Selenium) of 25+ websites of companies all around Europe and Geocoding, for the development of the client's new commercial tool.

Aug. – Sept. 2020 Data Scientist - S2DS Fellow

Remote

Successfully delivered team project for SEGRO plc to optimise client's portfolio through Manipulation & Visualization of Geospatial Data (GeoPandas, Folium, Shapely), Web-scraping, Geocoding and extensive use of APIs in Python.

2014 – Sept. 2020 Assistant Professor (Nuclear Astrophysics)

Extensive use of Python (NumPy, Matplotlib, SciPy, ...), Data Visualisation and Machine-Learning techniques (linear regression, confidence intervals, correlations, calibration and optimisation of multi-parameter models). Published 30+ articles in renowned international journals. gave 5+ invited talks, 20+ seminars/presentations around the world, and lectures in Physics at all levels across Europe.

Key contributor to winning grants (€1.2M in total).

Conceived and organised 3 international conferences (50-250 participants each).

Member of 3 European networks & 3 Space Mission projects.

Contributed to popularisation of astronomy (books, movies, interviews, translations).

Mentored female students in STEM from around the world.

2016 – Sept. 2020 Visiting Researcher

Completed 10+ projects including machine-learning aspects, acting as a bridge between Astrophysics and Nuclear Physics.

2012 - 2014**Postdoctoral Researcher** Rome (IT)

Worked as an independent researcher building contacts around the world.

Expanded my expertise from Astrophysics to include Nuclear Physics.